### SOFTWARE ENGINEER · DATA ANALYST

## Overview \_

I am experienced in deep learning, data analysis, data mining, data gathering, statistical modeling, machine learning, metric design, and natural language processing. I have extensive experience in gathering data using R and Python to build both predictive and explanatory statistical models, and I am an adept programmer in multiple languages.

## **Education**

University of California, Davis

Davis, California

Ph.D. Computer Science, 4.0 GPA

2013 - Present (Expected 2018)

**University of California, Davis** 

Davis, California

B.S. COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

2009 - 2013

### **Publications**.

Elements of Socio-Technical Trust in GitHub: The Effects of Visibility, Expertise, Productivity, and Responsiveness

Submitted MSR 2018

DAVID KAVALER, PREM DEVANBU, VLADIMIR FILKOV

A Study of Android App Success by Cross-Linking GitHub and Google Play Store

Submitted MSR 2018

JOHN BUSINGE, DAVID KAVALER, ENGINEER BAINOMUGISHA, VLADMIR FILKOV, MOSES OPENJA

Exploiting Time and Subject Locality for Fast, Efficient, and Understandable Alert Triage

Accepted ICNC 2018

DAVID KAVALER, COREY HUDSON, MICHAEL BIERMA

Perceived Language Complexity in GitHub Issue Discussions and Their Effect on Issue Resolution

Accepted ASE 2017

DAVID KAVALER, SASHA SIROVICA, VINCENT HELLENDOORN, RAUL ARANOVICH, VLADIMIR FILKOV

Submitted PLOS ONE

Quality, Latency, and Amount of Stack Overflow Answers to Questions About Recent Android APIs **DAVID KAVALER, VLADIMIR FILKOV** 

Under minor revisions

Stochastic Actor-Oriented Modeling for Studying Homophily and Social Influence in OSS Projects

Accepted to journal EMSE 2016

DAVID KAVALER, VLADIMIR FILKOV

• Invited to present at the International Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering (FSE) 2016.

Using and Asking: APIs Used in the Android Market and Asked About in StackOverflow

Accepted SocInfo 2013

DAVID KAVALER, DARYL POSNETT, CLINT GIBLER, HAO CHEN, PREM DEVANBU, VLADIMIR FILKOV

· Best paper nominee.

# Awards & Honors \_

2018 Invited Reviewer, PLOS ONE

2016 Invited Presentation, International Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering (FSE)

2015 Fellowship, UC Davis Graduate Group in Computer Science

2013 Fellowship, UC Davis Graduate Group in Computer Science

2013 Best Paper Nomination, International Conference on Social Informatics

## Work Experience.

# University of California, Davis

Davis, California

Sep. 2013 - Present

RESEARCH AND TEACHING ASSISTANT

- Research assistant in the DECAL lab at UC Davis.
- · Teaching assistant for multiple courses, including software engineering and introduction to object-oriented programming (C++).

## Sandia National Laboratories

Livermore, California

Jun. 2016 - Sep. 2016

CYBERSECURITY SUMMER RESEARCH INTERN

· Worked towards various solutions for cybersecurity related problems. Resulting paper accepted to ICNC 2018.

**Programming Languages** R, Python, C/C++, C#, Java, LaTeX, Javascript

Tools & Frameworks TensorFlow, keras, scikit-learn, PostgreSQL, Node.js, Android, Unity